Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katherine.
我是Katherine。
And Marco, today we're talking about a very important part of daily life.
Marco，今天我们聊的是日常生活中非常重要的一部分。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to take a look at a lesson about technology and something that has become
今天我们要看一节关于科技的课程，这个话题已经变得
so popular and part of our everyday lives that it's necessary for us to acknowledge
非常流行，成为我们日常生活的一部分，所以我们有必要用英语来了解它。
it in English.
没错。
That's right.
So we're talking about cellular phones, but not just cellular phones.
所以我们说的是手机，但不仅仅是手机。
Something you can do and that many people often do on their cellular phones.
而是你在手机上能做的一件事，也是很多人经常做的事。
That's right.
没错。
So before we get into that, let's listen to the dialogue, try to understand what it's
在我们深入之前，先来听一下对话，试着理解它
all about and we'll be back in a bit.
讲的是什么，我们一会儿回来。
Why didn't you text me last night?
你昨晚为什么不给我发短信？
What?
什么？
I sent you three or four messages.
我给你发了三四条消息。
I didn't get any of them.
我一条都没收到。
I was waiting for you to text me the address of where the party was and I never got your
我一直在等你给我发短信告诉我派对地址，但我一直没收到你的
message.
消息。
Why didn't you just call?
你为什么不直接打电话？
I hate sending SMS messages.
我讨厌发短信。
Well, because I didn't have any credit on my phone.
嗯，因为我手机里没话费了。
I used it all up this month.
这个月我用完了。
I thought you had an unlimited SMS plan.
我以为你有个无限短信套餐。
I do, but if I don't have any credit in my phone, it won't let me call or send messages.
我有，但如果我手机里没话费，它就不让我打电话或发消息。
No wonder you didn't get my texts.
难怪你没收到我的短信。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at Language Takeaway.
现在让我们来看看“语言要点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
First up on Language Takeaway, we have the verb that is the focus of today's dialogue,
首先在语言要点里，我们有一个动词，它是今天对话的重点，
to text.
就是“to text”。
That's right.
没错。
To text is a verb in this case, to text.
这里“to text”是一个动词，发短信。
Text me.
给我发短信。
Why didn't you text me?
你为什么不给我发短信？
Now remember that text means other things in other situations.
记住，“text”在其他情况下还有其他意思。
Here it's a verb.
这里它是动词。
It's a very new word as a verb from the last maybe 15 years or so with cell phones.
作为动词，它是一个很新的词，大概从过去15年左右随着手机出现。
So that's actually what it means is to send a text message via cell phone.
所以它的意思就是通过手机发送短信。
So you send a message.
所以你发送一条消息。
That's right.
没错。
You actually write the message, right?
你实际上是写消息，对吧？
It's not a call.
不是打电话。
When I call you, I talk to you.
当我打电话给你时，我跟你说话。
When you text someone, you actually write a message.
当你给某人发短信时，你实际上是写一条消息。
It's very short and then you send it and the other person can read it.
它很短，然后你发送，对方可以阅读。
Right.
对。
So instead of saying, why didn't you send me a text message last night?
所以与其说“你昨晚为什么不给我发一条短信？”
We just say, why didn't you text me?
我们只说“你昨晚为什么不给我发短信？”
All right.
好的。
Now, another word that we often hear about texts is the noun messages or message.
现在，另一个我们经常听到的关于短信的词是名词“messages”或“message”。
So I sent you three or four messages.
所以我给你发了三四条消息。
That's right.
没错。
So when we're talking about texting someone, what we're doing is sending a message.
所以当我们说给某人发短信时，我们做的是发送一条消息。
A text message.
一条短信。
That's right.
没错。
Because we can send a voice message.
因为我们可以发送语音消息。
That's right.
没错。
So voice is me talking, hi Marco, it's Catherine.
所以语音就是我在说话，嗨Marco，我是Catherine。
How are you doing?
你好吗？
Right.
对。
But a text message is actually words.
但短信实际上是文字。
I write them out.
我写出来。
That's right.
没错。
So, but then we could actually use the verb form as well.
所以，但我们也可以使用动词形式。
So we can say to text or we can say to message.
所以我们可以说“to text”或者“to message”。
Why didn't you message me last night?
你昨晚为什么不给我发消息？
That's right.
没错。
So we use this slang to message someone because text is very common and everyone uses it.
所以我们用这个俚语“to message someone”，因为“text”很常见，大家都用。
But normally young people say, hey, why didn't you message me?
但通常年轻人会说，嘿，你为什么不给我发消息？
Or aren't you ever going to message me?
或者你永远不给我发消息吗？
Right, right, right.
对，对，对。
Or stop messaging in class.
或者上课别发消息了。
That's right.
没错。
So these are verbs to text and to message.
所以这些是动词“to text”和“to message”。
That's right.
没错。
Now, if we see down towards the middle of the dialogue, we see that the person hates
现在，如果我们看对话中间部分，会发现这个人讨厌
sending SMS messages.
发短信。
So it's kind of explaining already what's been said because you have SMS messages and
这其实是在解释之前说的内容，因为提到了短信，而
this abbreviation stands for?
这个缩写代表什么？
Short message service.
短消息服务。
Short S, message M, service S. So short message service.
短 S，消息 M，服务 S。所以是短消息服务。
But most people around the world say SMS.
但世界上大多数人还是说 SMS。
Right.
对。
So they say, oh, send me an SMS or send me an SMS message, which again, like we see in
所以他们会说，哦，给我发个 SMS 或给我发个 SMS 消息，这就像我们在
the dialogue, it's kind of contradictory because we're already saying short message service
对话中看到的，有点矛盾，因为我们已经在说短消息服务
message.
消息了。
Yeah, but most people don't know what SMS means.
是啊，但大多数人不知道 SMS 是什么意思。
So they just say, hey, send me an SMS message or send me a text message or I didn't get
所以他们就说，嘿，给我发个 SMS 消息或发个短信，或者我没收到
your SMS.
你的 SMS。
That's right.
没错。
Now, lastly, we didn't get the SMS because we didn't have any credit on the phone.
最后，我们没收到短信是因为手机里没话费了。
All right.
好的。
Now, credit is an important word here.
这里“话费”是个关键词。
It's a noun.
它是名词。
It's a thing.
是个东西。
We have credit or we don't have credit.
我们有话费或没有话费。
And it's important to remember that credit stands for money.
要记住，话费代表钱。
All right.
好的。
So maybe I buy $10 of credit for my cell phone and that means I can send many, many messages.
所以可能我给我的手机充了 10 美元的话费，这意味着我可以发很多很多消息。
But when I have zero credit, I can't send any messages.
但当我话费为零时，我就发不了任何消息了。
That's right.
没错。
So this is important because usually in many places you have to have this amount of money
这很重要，因为通常在很多地方，你的手机里必须有这么多钱
in your phone in order to be able to talk and send messages.
才能打电话和发消息。
So this money that you have is called credit.
所以这笔钱就叫话费。
So you can say, I don't have any credit on my phone.
你可以说，我手机里没话费了。
That's right.
没错。
And it's basically a way of having money without having real money.
这基本上是一种不用真钱也能拥有钱的方式。
You actually buy credit from your cell phone provider like AT&T or if you have China Telecom,
你实际上是从你的手机运营商那里买话费，比如 AT&T 或者如果你用中国电信，
that's who you buy credit from.
就是向他们买话费。
That's right.
没错。
Very good.
很好。
So let's get into the dialogue again and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
那我们再回到对话，稍后我们会回来讲流利度训练。
Why didn't you text me last night?
你昨晚为什么不给我发短信？
What?
什么？
I sent you three or four messages.
我给你发了三四条消息。
I didn't get any of them.
我一条都没收到。
I was waiting for you to text me the address of where the party was and I never got your
我一直在等你发短信告诉我派对地址，但我一直没收到你的
message.
消息。
Why didn't you just call?
你为什么不直接打电话？
I hate sending SMS messages.
我讨厌发短信。
Well, because I didn't have any credit on my phone.
嗯，因为我手机里没话费了。
I used it all up this month.
这个月都用完了。
I thought you had an unlimited SMS plan.
我以为你有个无限短信套餐。
I do.
我是有。
I don't have any credit in my phone, it won't let me call or send messages.
但我手机里没话费了，它不让我打电话或发消息。
No wonder you didn't get my texts.
难怪你没收到我的短信。
All right, we've prepared three phrases for you.
好的，我们为你准备了三个短语。
Let's start with those now in Fluency Builder.
现在在流利度训练中开始讲这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
So we're still talking about credit here.
所以我们还在讨论话费。
Now when you have credit, you can use it.
当你有话费时，你可以用它。
But if you use all of it, we say you use it all up.
但如果你用完了所有话费，我们就说“用光”。
Right.
对。
We used it up.
我们用光了。
To use something up.
用光某物。
So here, what does the up do?
那么这里的“光”起什么作用？
Because we can use something, like I'm using my toothbrush, but to use up is different.
因为我们可以用某物，比如我在用我的牙刷，但“用光”是不同的。
Right, it means that you finished it.
对，它意味着你用完了。
It no longer exists.
它不再存在了。
So it's completed.
所以是完成了。
I had credit, I used it up, that means it is gone.
我有话费，我用光了，意思就是没了。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So for example, maybe paint.
比如，可能是油漆。
You're painting a room and you used up all the white paint.
你在刷房间，用光了所有白色油漆。
So you used all the paint, you have no more paint.
所以你用了所有油漆，没有更多油漆了。
It's gone, so it's all used up.
没了，所以全用光了。
It's a very important phrase to remember, it's used up.
这是一个很重要的短语要记住，就是“用光”。
That's right.
没错。
Now going back to SMS and messages, the question came up and said, I thought you had an unlimited
现在回到短信和消息，问题出现了，有人说，我以为你有个无限
SMS plan.
短信套餐。
All right, so an unlimited SMS plan.
好的，所以是无限短信套餐。
We know what SMS means, but first of all, let's talk about a plan.
我们知道 SMS 是什么意思，但首先，我们来谈谈“套餐”。
Because when we talk about cell phones, it's important to remember that some people buy
因为当我们谈论手机时，要记住有些人买
credit, that's how they get service.
话费，那是他们获得服务的方式。
But some people buy plans.
但有些人买套餐。
This is very popular, by the way, in America, this is how most phones are.
顺便说一句，这在美国非常流行，大多数手机都是这样的。
What is a plan?
什么是套餐？
So basically, it's just like any other service, like maybe internet.
所以基本上，它就像其他服务一样，比如互联网。
You pay a monthly fee and you get a certain amount of this service.
你每月支付一笔费用，就能获得一定量的服务。
So maybe you pay $50 and you get 100 minutes to use on your cell phone, an unlimited amount
比如你可能付50美元，就能在手机上使用100分钟通话，以及无限量
of SMS.
的短信。
All right, so basically, my cell phone provider, AT&T or Telecom, they will say, for this
好的，所以基本上，我的手机运营商，比如AT&T或电信公司，他们会说，对于这个
price, you get this much time, this many messages each month, and you have to keep paying it.
价格，你每月能得到这么多通话时间和这么多短信，而且你必须持续付费。
Normally, it's one year or two years that you have to commit.
通常，你需要承诺使用一年或两年。
You can't say, nah, I don't want this anymore.
你不能说，算了，我不想用了。
But the important thing here is that the person bought an unlimited SMS plan.
但这里的关键是，这个人买了一个无限短信套餐。
So this keyword there, unlimited, means it has no limit.
所以这个关键词“无限”，意思是它没有限制。
It means you can use it as much as you want.
意思是你想用多少就用多少。
So unlimited, no limits, that means you can do it as much as you want.
所以无限，没有限制，意味着你可以随心所欲地使用。
You can have unlimited calls, you get unlimited SMS, you can have unlimited data, for example.
比如，你可以有无限通话、无限短信、无限流量。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good.
很好。
And we end it with saying, well, no wonder you didn't get my text.
最后我们总结说，难怪你没收到我的短信。
Well, because he didn't have credit.
嗯，因为他没有话费了。
No wonder you didn't get it.
难怪你没收到。
I know wonder is a great and very important phrase, and it's something we say when we
我知道“难怪”是一个很棒且非常重要的短语，当我们
finally understand why something happened.
终于明白某事发生的原因时，就会用到它。
Right, we realize what happened.
对，我们意识到发生了什么。
So Marco, gosh, why didn't you respond to my calls?
所以马可，天哪，你为什么不接我的电话？
Well, I didn't have any credit.
嗯，我没有话费了。
No wonder.
难怪。
That means, oh, now I understand.
意思是，哦，现在我明白了。
No wonder.
难怪。
Exactly.
没错。
It's a great phrase to start off your sentence by explaining or letting the other person
这是一个很棒的短语，可以用它来开始你的句子，解释或让对方
know that you finally understand why this happened or you understand what the situation
知道你终于明白为什么发生这件事，或者你理解了当时的情况
was.
是怎样的。
All right, so let's take a listen to the dialogue one last time.
好了，让我们最后再听一遍对话。
Why didn't you text me last night?
你昨晚为什么不给我发短信？
What?
什么？
I sent you three or four messages.
我给你发了三四条消息。
I didn't get any of them.
我一个都没收到。
I was waiting for you to text me the address of where the party was and I never got your
我一直在等你发短信告诉我派对地址，但我一直没收到你的
message.
消息。
Why didn't you just call?
你为什么不直接打电话？
I hate sending SMS messages.
我讨厌发短信。
Well, because I didn't have any credit on my phone.
嗯，因为我手机没话费了。
I used it all up this month.
这个月我用完了。
I thought you had an unlimited SMS plan.
我以为你有一个无限短信套餐。
I do, but if I don't have any credit in my phone, it won't let me call or send messages.
我有，但如果我手机里没有话费，它就不让我打电话或发消息。
No wonder you didn't get my texts.
难怪你没收到我的短信。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So talking about messages and everything, do you send a lot of messages?
说到消息和这些，你经常发消息吗？
Because I know some people who send like 100 messages a day.
因为我知道有些人一天发100条消息。
Well, that's usually teenagers.
嗯，那通常是青少年。
Yeah, I don't send 100 messages a day.
是啊，我一天不发100条消息。
I mostly use messages.
我主要用消息。
I don't call people very often.
我不经常打电话。
I find that messages are easier and cheaper, actually.
我发现消息更方便，实际上也更便宜。
But I can't imagine sending a thousand messages a day or a hundred messages a day.
但我无法想象一天发一千条或一百条消息。
Your thumbs would get so tired.
你的拇指会累坏的。
Well, I remember, well, this is back in the day when you had the little Nokia phones and
嗯，我记得，那是以前，当你用那种小诺基亚手机，
you didn't have the touch screens and all this stuff.
还没有触摸屏这些东西的时候。
I did have some friends who were very, very agile with sending these messages and some
我确实有一些朋友，他们发消息非常非常灵活，有些人
did send, I don't know, 100, 200 messages a day because it was that new way of communicating
一天发，我不知道，100、200条消息，因为那是与人交流的新方式
with people.
。
Yeah, it's very exciting.
是啊，非常令人兴奋。
And I will also mention, and this is something that my parents complain about, there is something
我还要提一下，这是我父母抱怨的事情，在美国
in America and I'm sure in England as well called text talk or text speak.
有一种叫“短信用语”或“短信缩写”的东西，我相信在英国也一样。
And so because messages are short, people have started to change the way they spell
因为消息很短，人们开始改变拼写
or write words.
或书写单词的方式。
So instead of saying F-O-R, this is for you, they write, this is number for you.
所以不说F-O-R，这是给你的，他们写，这是数字4给你。
And it's so funny because you see these normal words but written in a strange new way.
这很有趣，因为你看到这些正常的单词，却用一种奇怪的新方式写出来。
And people who are older, I think my parents' age, and I do too to some extent, really don't
而年纪大一点的人，我想像我父母这个年纪，以及我在某种程度上也这样，真的不
like it because it's so different.
喜欢它，因为它太不同了。
It's especially very popular with the younger generation because it translates now to all
这在年轻一代中尤其流行，因为它现在已经延伸到各种
sorts of messaging.
消息传递中。
So before, as you say, it was because of the limitations, the amount of characters you
所以以前，如你所说，是因为限制，一条消息能发送的字符数
could send in a message.
有限。
But now it's just become something that people have gotten in the habit of doing.
但现在这已经成为人们养成的习惯了。
So for example, instead of writing skate, like skateboard, they would write S-K and
比如，不写skate，像滑板，他们会写S-K和
then the number eight.
数字8。
So skate.
所以是skate。
That's right.
没错。
Skate.
Skate。
滑冰。
It's so strange.
这太奇怪了。
And I know it actually happens in other languages as well.
而且我知道其他语言里其实也有这种情况。
Yeah, a lot.
是啊，很多。
Italian, they do it a lot.
意大利语里，他们经常这样用。
And Spanish, I'm sure as well.
西班牙语肯定也是。
But we call it text speak because it's very, very short and kind of abbreviated.
但我们管它叫“短信体”，因为它非常非常简短，有点缩写的感觉。
But it's a problem from my understanding is because these younger generations, they use
但据我理解，问题在于这些年轻一代用得太多了，
it so much that they really kind of start forgetting the proper grammar and proper spelling.
以至于他们真的开始有点忘记正确的语法和拼写了。
So even you will find, I saw a report the other day, essays or reports handed in with
所以甚至你会发现，我前几天看到一份报告，交上来的论文或报告里
these terrible spelling mistakes.
全是这些可怕的拼写错误。
That's awful.
那太糟糕了。
Well, I hope, hope, hope that people are learning grammar and spelling, especially non-native
嗯，我希望、希望、希望人们能学好语法和拼写，尤其是非母语的
learners of English.
英语学习者。
So if you're doing homework for your English class, don't use these.
所以如果你在做英语课的作业，别用这些。
But it might be interesting to look them up.
但查一查它们可能会挺有意思的。
So let us know though, do you text message people?
那么告诉我们吧，你会发短信给别人吗？
Do you send these text messages?
你会发这些短信吗？
Do you have SMS service in your country?
你们国家有短信服务吗？
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好了。
We'll see you guys there.
我们那儿见。
Bye.
再见。
Thank you.
谢谢。